Guide to the Yasser Alwan Collection AD.MC.002
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- Series II: Egypt, 1895-1971 (Box 1-7)
  - Two young women with short haircuts in white dresses. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid338 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; Girls; Jewelry; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Clocks/Watches; Group Portraits; Women
  - A portrait of a man posed next to a woman seated on an ornate chair. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid339 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Painted Backdrops; Men; Head Covers/Veils; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Furnishings; Women; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Tiles; Hats
  - A family group, two men wearing tarbouches and one woman wearing a light dress. 13.4 x 8.4 cm, 8 June 1917; cuid340 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Group Portraits; Egypt; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Fez/Tarboush; Arabic Writing; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Furnishings; Signatures; Jewelry; Hats
  - A man wearing a tuxedo and tarbouche with a boy, both holding a book. 13.6 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid341 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Fez/Tarboush; Men; Boys; Painted Backdrops; Books; Furnishings; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Children; Bow Ties; Tuxedos; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Hats
  - A boy wearing a coat and tarbouche, holding flowers. 13.8 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid342 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Fez/Tarboush; Studio Photography; Furnishings; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Egypt; Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Children; Photographic Prints; Hats
  - A girl in a white dress with a veil. 13.8 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid343 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Studio Photography; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry; Furnishings; Head Covers/Veils; Photographic Prints; Girls; Children; Religious Ceremony
  - Two young women posing in a garden. 13.8 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid344 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Hats; Bags/Purses; Photographic Prints; Women; Group Portraits; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gardens; Outdoors; Clocks/Watches
  - A bride and groom. 13.8 x 8.8 cm, 19 February 1942; cuid345 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Weddings; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Women; Photographic Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Women; Weddings; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Weddings; Studio Photography; Men; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A woman looking off camera, with her hands on her hips, in a home setting. 13.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid346 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Jewelry; Furnishings; Egypt; Head Covers/Veils; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Houses
  - A woman with three children standing by a wall. 14.0 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid347 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Group Portraits; Jewelry
  - A portrait of a man and a woman posing in their bathing suits at the beach. 13.1 x 8.2 cm, Undated; cuid348 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Egypt; Men; Photographic Prints; Seas; Swimming; Hats; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Beaches; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A group of men, some wearing pith helmets, others wearing tarbouches, and a man wearing a Greek Orthodox kamilavkion. 8.7 x 14.2 cm, Undated; cuid349 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Fez/Tarboush; Orthodox Christianity; Priests/Clergymen; Hats; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Umbrellas/Parasols
  - A man with a cane, wearing a tarbouche and a suit. 13.4 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid350 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Hats; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Canes/Walking Sticks; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Men; Individual Portraits; Fez/Tarboush; Studio Photography; Cairo, Egypt; Facial Hair
  - A man in a robe, tarbouche and sash with a cresent moon and three stars. 13.5 x 8.6 cm, Circa 1922 - 1952; cuid351 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Individual Portraits; Men; Flags; Painted Backdrops; Cairo, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Studio Photography; Academic Dress; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Facial Hair; Medals/Insignia; Hats
  - A man in a three-piece suit and a pocket watch. London Studio, Cairo, Egypt. 13.3 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid352 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Painted Backdrops; Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair
  - A man in military uniform, holding a sword (linked ref381, ref387, ref388). 13.5 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid353 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Photographic Prints; Gloves; Swords/Knives; Fez/Tarboush; Studio Photography; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Egypt; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Medals/Insignia; Facial Hair; Weapons; Hats
  - A man in military uniform and a tarbouche (linked ref380, ref387, ref388). 13.8 x 8.2 cm, Undated; cuid354 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Fez/Tarboush; Studio Photography; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Medals/Insignia; Individual Portraits; Men; Facial Hair; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Hats
  - Two women looking off camera, holding hands. 13.4 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid356 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Women; Group Portraits; Studio Photography; Jewelry; Egypt; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A woman with separated eyelashes, looking off camera. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid357 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Jewelry; Women; Individual Portraits; Cairo, Egypt
  - Two women, one standing and one sitting, while resting her feet on a cushion. 13.7 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid358 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Suez, Egypt; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Women; Group Portraits; Carpets/Rugs
  - Two men in tarbouches and suits, resting on a railing. 8.7 x 13.7 cm, Undated; cuid359 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Photographic Prints; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Studio Photography; Men; Jewelry; Fez/Tarboush; Painted Backdrops; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Furnishings; Medals/Insignia; Hats
  - Two men and a boy sitting with a book in his hand (linked ref380, ref381, ref388). 13.2 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid360 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Books; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Regional/National Dress; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boys; Men; Studio Photography; Fez/Tarboush; Children; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Furnishings; Tiles; Hats
  - Three men and a boy. Two men and boy from ref387, with a seated man from ref380 and ref381 in military uniform (linked ref380, ref381, ref387). 13.1 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid361 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Painted Backdrops; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Regional/National Dress; Fez/Tarboush; Studio Photography; Men; Group Portraits; Boys; Children; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A multi-generational group sitting at a table in restaurant. 8.3 x 14.2 cm, Undated; cuid362 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Restaurants/bars; Fez/Tarboush; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Children; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Jewelry; Hats
  - A portrait of a man and a woman sitting in a park. 8.8 x 13.9 cm, Undated; cuid363 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Jewelry; Parks; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A studio portrait of a man wearing glasses sitting with a girl wearing a dress. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid364 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Bow Ties; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Group Portraits
  - A portrait of a man and a woman posed in front of a window. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid365 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Men; Studio Photography; Jewelry; Heliopolis, Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A group of two men and three children, sitting on a pavement in front of a park. 8.0 x 13.0 cm, Undated; cuid366 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Egypt; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Boys; Photographic Prints; Girls; Parks; Men; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A group of wheelwrights, making wooden wheels. 8.8 x 12.0 cm, Undated; cuid367 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Regional/National Dress; Workers; Men; Group Portraits; Turbans
  - Two girls wearing matching dresses, with a boy. 13.4 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid368 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Studio Photography; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Girls; Boys; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Furnishings; Maritime/Nautical Outfits
  - A ribbon cutting ceremony. 8.7 x 13.7 cm, Undated; cuid369 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Men; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Regional/National Dress; Gelatin Silver Prints; Audiences/Spectators; Crowds; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Events/Occasions; Ceremonies; Fez/Tarboush; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A woman with three children, holding a milk bottle. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid370 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Dogs; Painted Backdrops; Children; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Toys; Women; Group Portraits; Animals; Furnishings; Drinks/Beverages
  - A family group, a boy is holding a hoop. 13.6 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid371 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Children; Facial Hair; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Toys; Boys; Men; Women; Studio Photography; Group Portraits; Furnishings; Jewelry
  - A man in military uniform and a tarbouche. 13.5 x 8.7 cm, 12 December 1939; cuid372 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Fez/Tarboush; Photographic Prints; Asyut, Egypt; Men; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Swords/Knives; Studio Photography; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair; Weapons; Medals/Insignia; Carpets/Rugs; Weapons; Hats
  - A man in a military uniform holding a cane. 14.1 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid373 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Studio Photography; Facial Hair; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Furnishings; Uniforms; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Men; Individual Portraits; Fez/Tarboush; Navy; Canes/Walking Sticks; Military/Soldiers; Tiles; Hats
  - Four women on a swan carousel, with a flag of Egypt (1923-1952) in the background. 8.2 x 11.0 cm, cuid374 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Buildings; Egypt; Flags; Women; Photographic Prints; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits
  - A man with three boys in matching outfits and a girl sitting in a chair. 13.9 x 9.1 cm, Undated; cuid375 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Girls; Boys; Studio Photography; Furnishings; Fez/Tarboush; Painted Backdrops; Children; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Facial Hair; Hats; Carpets/Rugs
  - A man and a woman posing in a Bedouin costume, the man holds a sword and a gun, and the woman holds a water pot. 13.5 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid376 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Men; Studio Photography; Costumes; Weapons; Swords/Knives; Guns; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Tiles; Carpets/Rugs; Pottery; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Furnishings
  - An elderly woman in a garden with a flower in her hand. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid377 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Women; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Gardens; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits
  - A man wearing a bowler hat standing in a park, with a bird on his right arm. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid378 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Animals; Egypt; Hats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Parks; Birds; Men
  - A boy posing as a Greek soldier. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid379 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Children; Boys; Costumes; Weapons; Regional/National Dress; Guns; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints
  - A man wearing a sash resting on a tall side table. 13.5 x 8.4 cm, 31 October 1914; cuid380 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Studio Photography; Fez/Tarboush; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Men; Medals/Insignia; Facial Hair; Furnishings; Signatures; Bow Ties; Hats
  - A boy with a doll, standing on some stairs. 13.4 x 8.5 cm, 1936; cuid381 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Children; Boys; Hats; Arabic Writing; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Toys
  - A girl wearing a sequined dress kneeling on a leopard skin rug. 13.3 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid382 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Individual Portraits; Girls; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Arabic Writing; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Carpets/Rugs
  - A woman resting on a folding screen. Signed by the same person as ref411, Elise Bruno. 13.5 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid383 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Painted Backdrops; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Signatures; Women; Furnishings; Studio Photography; Greek Writing
  - A woman resting on a chair with a tall back. Signed by the same person as ref410, Elise Bruno. 13.7 x 8.2 cm, Undated; cuid384 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Painted Backdrops; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; Jewelry; Women; Greek Writing; Signatures
  - A girl wearing a nautical outfit. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid385 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Egypt; Greek Writing; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Girls; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints
  - Notre Dame du Liban, Janto in Harissa, Lebanon. Armenian text on reverse: My dear Perchuhi. I am sending you this picture of famous Notre-Dame du Liban. How are you? How is everything? We are all awaiting letters from you. Kisses to everyone. Signed Rosa Askian. 14.0 x 8.9 cm, 7 August 1937; cuid386 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Signatures; Postcards; Harissa, Lebanon; Armenian Writing; Religious Sites; Statues/Sculptures
  - A family group, with two girls wearing matching dresses. 13.6 x 8.7 cm, 11 April 1909; cuid387 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Boys; Girls; Children; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Carpets/Rugs; Jewelry
  - Women and children sitting on the beach. 13.7 x 8.8 cm, 1946; cuid388 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Buildings; Group Portraits; Children; Women; Beaches; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A woman standing on a rooftop next to a table and a dog. 8.7 x 6.1 cm, 12 March 1932; cuid389 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Buildings; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Animals; Jewelry; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Egypt; Dogs; Arabic Writing; Signatures
  - The funeral of Boghos Pasha Nubar (Chairman of the Armenian National Assembly, co-founder of the Armenian National Movement). 9.0 x 14.0 cm, June 1930; cuid390 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Funeral Proceedings; Carriages/Coaches; Horses; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Paris, France; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Coffins/Caskets; Animals; Gelatin Silver Prints; Pasha; Armenian Writing; Crowds; Men; Women; Hats; Police; Group Portraits; Nubar, Boghos, Pasha, 1851-1930
  - A group of schoolboys with three men, one is a clergyman wearing a kalimavkion. College Patriarchal Grec Catholique de Bienfaisange, Caire. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid391 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Orthodox Christianity; Priests/Clergymen; Boys; Children; Schools/Education; Gelatin Silver Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Group Portraits; Men; Facial Hair; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Hats
  - A woman in a long dress with a black belt. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid392 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Arabic Writing; Women; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Signatures
  - A young man in military uniform and a tarbouche. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, 1949; cuid393 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Gloves; Uniforms; Gelatin Silver Prints; Military/Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Abdin, Cairo, Egypt; Studio Photography; Fez/Tarboush; Individual Portraits; Men; Hats
  - Three women in a studio portrait. 13.4 x 8.2 cm, 12 March 1926; cuid394 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Greek Writing; Furnishings; Women; Jewelry; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Studio Photography; Group Portraits
  - A family portrait. 8.7 x 13.6 cm, 15 August 1943; cuid395 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Painted Backdrops; Girls; Women; Men; Boys; Fez/Tarboush; Signatures; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Head Covers/Veils; Children; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Jewelry; Hats
  - Four women and three men posing on a beach. 8.4 x 13.2 cm, 1948; cuid396 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Seas; Arabic Writing; Swimming; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Signatures; Women; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Egypt; Beaches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair
  - A man with round glasses wearing a double-breasted suit. 13.8 x 8.6 cm, 29 (?) 1933; cuid397 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Men; Arabic Writing; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Tiles
  - A Baptism ceremony for a baby. 8.8 x 13.5 cm, 8 December 1954; cuid398 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Women; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Events/Occasions; Photographic Prints; Priests/Clergymen; Italian Writing; Children; Alexandria, Egypt; Baptisms; Facial Hair; Group Portraits
  - A girl sitting on the stairs holding a doll (linked ref427 and ref428) 13.6 x 8.4 cm, 7th (?) 1952; cuid399 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Girls; Photographic Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Children; Toys
  - A girl sitting on the stairs holding a doll (linked ref426 and ref428). 13.2 x 8.4 cm, 7 January 1952; cuid400 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Cairo, Egypt; Girls; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Children; Toys
  - A girl sitting on the stairs holding a doll (linked ref426 and ref427). 13.6 x 8.3 cm, 1952; cuid401 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Studio Photography; Arabic Writing; Girls; Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Group Portraits; Toys; Children
  - An Armenian woman with a parasol. 13.8 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid402 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Umbrellas/Parasols; Individual Portraits; Alexandria, Egypt; Postcards; Studio Photography; Signatures; Armenian Writing; Women; Painted Backdrops; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Furnishings
  - Seven men in suits, sitting in a garden. 9.2 x 14.5 cm, Undated; cuid403 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Gardens; Group Portraits; Buildings; Fountains; Men; Photographic Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Egypt; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A boy wearing a galabeya and tarbouche. 13.5 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid412 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Regional/National Dress; Fez/Tarboush; Painted Backdrops; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Boys; Furnishings; Children; Hats
  - A man smoking a cigarette, sitting next to books, a recording device and a radio. 8.5 x 13.5 cm, Undated; cuid413 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Fez/Tarboush; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Clocks/Watches; Egypt; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Cigarettes; Radios; Furnishings; Books; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Hats
  - A young man in a suit and tie with wavy hair. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, 14 May 1933; cuid414 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Arabic Writing; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Men; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Signatures
  - A man wearing a suit and tarbouche. 14.0 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid415 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Men; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Painted Backdrops; Fez/Tarboush; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A boy on a tricycle. 14.0 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid416 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Arabic Writing; Bicycles/Tricycles; Boys; Bicycles/Tricycles; Individual Portraits; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Photographic Prints; Tiles
  - Two women and seven children on a terrace. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid417 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Children; Women; Photographic Prints; Girls; Boys; Egypt; Head Covers/Veils; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Doors/Entrances
  - A boy, seated with his legs crossed. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid418 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Heliopolis, Cairo, Egypt; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Fez/Tarboush; Boys; Children; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Hats
  - A family group pose at the top of some stairs in front of a bulding.13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid419 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Photographic Prints; French Writing; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Architecture; Buildings; Doors/Entrances; Group Portraits; Women; Men
  - A young woman in a patterned dress, looking off camera. 13.3 x 8.4 cm, 3 October 1930; cuid420 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    French Writing; Jewelry; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Suez, Egypt; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Signatures
  - A woman in a polka dot dress with a large bow. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, 20 February 1930; cuid421 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Women; Painted Backdrops; Individual Portraits; Italian Writing
  - Three young men reading a Kodak guide. 13.8 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid422 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Boys; Children; Photographic Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Advertisements; Newspapers/Magazines; Furnishings; Clocks/Watches
  - A bride and groom on a stepped platform. 14.0 x 8.6 cm, 11 December 1937; cuid423 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Cairo, Egypt; Italian Writing; Photographic Prints; Weddings; Studio Photography; Weddings; Women; Weddings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Men
  - A woman wearing a wide-brimmed hat, holding a parasol. 13.4 x 8.5 cm, 5 August 1931; cuid424 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Hats; Women; French Writing; Umbrellas/Parasols; Furnishings
  - Two boys dressed as French Foreign Legion soldiers. 13.7 x 8.5 cm, 10 June 1922; cuid425 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    French Writing; Children; Studio Photography; Costumes; Photographic Prints; Cáceres, Spain; Flags; Guns; Uniforms; Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Weapons; Painted Backdrops; Group Portraits; Military/Soldiers; Furnishings; Signatures
  - A young woman wearing a striped dress and beaded necklace. 13.9 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid426 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Port Said, Egypt; Jewelry; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Furnishings; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Painted Backdrops
  - A young man in a suit, with his hands behind his back. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, 30 July 1924; cuid427 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Individual Portraits; Men; Egypt; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Bow Ties; Furnishings; Signatures